easyengineering.net 2017-10-08

# Privacy policy – EasyEngineering

**This “Privacy Policy” was last modified on 2 nd October 2017**

This website [http://easyengineering.net](http://easyengineering.net/) is owned and operated by **  A Group of Civil Engineering Community**. We are committed to the privacy and security of our visitors information. This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect from the user(s) (“ **User(s)** ” and/or “ **You** ”) of the Website. Also read our “Terms of Service” available at <http://easyengineering.net/terms>

Our privacy policy answers/concludes the following important questions/sections to protect your privacy information in compliance with privacy laws,

**The following are the statement of our privacy practices:**

**What information do we collect?**

We collect information from you when you register on our site or fill out a form.

When registering on this site you are only required to provide your name ,username, password and email address, other details we ask are not required at any more, but you may/may not provide other details, even if have provided or want to provide other details, you have great control over the information that you have provided including email address. You can control who can see or who cannot see your personal information.

When filling out a form like contact form in [http://www.easyengineering.net](http://easyengineering.net/), you are required to provide your name and email address and your content regarding the purpose of contact. We do not store any information filling in forms but it is used to solve your inquiry, report or any other purpose.

Your personal information is not required to visit [http://easyengineering.net](http://easyengineering.net/). Any personal information collected is knowingly provided by you and only when requested/required during account registration for interactive participation on [http://www.easyengineering.net ****](http://easyengineering.net/).

Your IP address is a numeric address assigned to your computer, assigned by your Internet service provider. We automatically collect your IP address as traffic data so that we can send information back to you when requested. This is not used to identify your personal information. Referrers are references to the web address you linked from and are automatically passed along by your web browser. We collect referrers your browser sends as part of traffic data. This is not attached to personally identifiable information. System information such as your operating system/platform, and the type of web browser you use. This is not attached to personally identifiable information.

**Why do we collect your information?**

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  1. To personalize your experience (your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)
  2. To improve our website and send periodic emails (we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)
  3. The email address you provide may be used to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

**How do we protect your information?**

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you enter, submit, or access your personal information. To ensure correct use of information, we will employ reasonable and practicable security procedures and technologies. Your information is maintained on a secure web server in what we believe to be a well protected environment. We take every precaution to protect our visitor’s information. When visitors submit sensitive information via the web site, their information is protected both online and off-line. We do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line.

Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our support representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment, in a locked facility. If visitors have any questions about the security on [http://easyengineering.net](http://www.easyengineering.net/) , feel free to contact us. Correcting, Updating, Deleting & Deactivating Personal Information, If a visitor’s personally identifiable information changes or if a visitor no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate personally identifiable information.

**Do we use cookies on your browser?**

We do not use any cookies that help us to strive the information about your periodic visit, but on your preference the cookies may be stored on your website browser that can be controlled entirely by you.

**Cookies and third Party Advertisements**  : Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). We allow third-party companies to serve ads when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information.

Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to your website. Google’s use of the Double Click cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the Double Click cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the [ads preference manager](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). [http://www.easyengineering.net](http://www.easyengineering.net/) relies on “cookie” technology to allow you to re-access your registered account profile during a web session. This mechanism is employed solely for your convenience and for no other purpose.

**Do we share/disclose any information to outside parties?**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. No information is shared with any other third-party company for any purpose, under any circumstance. We make every effort to preserve your privacy, personal information may be disclosed when required by law where we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process.

**Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. We seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites. This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our visitors to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site [http://www.easyengineering.net](http://www.easyengineering.net/).

**User’s choice**

While filling a form/registering on our website, your name and e-mail address are mandatory for any queries/questions/complaints. The information other than name and e-mail address are user’s choice, they may enter/may not enter those informations while filling a form as mentioned above.

**Website User Consent**

By using our site ([http://www.easyengineering.net](http://www.easyengineering.net/)), website user/you consent to our web site privacy policy.

**Changes on Privacy Policy**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, so our visitors are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If, however, we are going to use visitors’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated in this policy at the time of collection we will notify users.

**If there are any questions regarding this “Privacy Policy” you may contact us using the contact form.**
